Hello. I'm Dr. Michael Clarkson. Welcome to
Functional Programming in OCaml. My main job
is teaching university students to write
correct,
efficient, and beautiful programs. In the
last
few years, I've taught OCaml to about 3 ,700
students at Cornell University in a course
titled CS3110, Data Structures and Functional
Programming.
You might have come across this video in any
number of ways. Maybe you're actually a
student
in CS 3110 right now. Maybe you're not a
Cornell student, but you're looking to learn
something about functional programming. Maybe
you came here from the online textbook in
which this video is embedded, or maybe you
found the video first. In which case, check
the comments below for the current link to
the textbook. I've been writing the textbook
for a few years now. It's based on course
notes written by myself and other faculty for
over two decades. Beyond teaching functional
programming, our goal has long been to teach
students to be great programmers, to equip
them with the knowledge, skills, and habits
they need to be successful beyond the basics
of the usual introductory computer science
classes.
These videos, however, are new. They came
about
because of pandemic. In the 2020 through 2021
academic  year,
I taught an asynchronous version of my class.
That meant these videos had to replace the
usual in -person lectures. So I ended up
producing
over 200 short videos, most around five to
six minutes in length. And the reaction from
students was overwhelmingly positive. So now
I'm making the videos publicly available for
anyone who wants to learn something about
OCaml,
functional programming, and becoming a better
programmer.
I hope you find them useful, maybe even
entertaining.
They are a love letter for me to all the
students who endured through the time of Zoom
U. We did it together. And now, maybe the
world can be just a bit better as we spread
the  light  of  functional  programming.